Guide to the General Frederick Steele Papers, 1845-1965 (inclusive), 1862-1868 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
General Frederick Steele Papers,
1845-1965 (inclusive), 1862-1868 (bulk)
Special Collections M0191
Steele, Frederick, 1819-1868.
10.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Catherine B. Steele, 1968-1972.
Biography
1819, Jan. 14 Born at Delhi, Delaware Co., N.Y. Son of Nathanial S. and descendent of John S., a founder of Hartford, Conn.
1839 Appointed cadet at West Point.
1843, July 1 Graduated from West Point; commissioned 2nd lieutenant, 2nd infantry.
1846-47 Mexican War. In action at Ocalaca, Contreras, Churubusco, Molino del Rey and Chapultepec. Twice brevetted for gallant conduct (Contreras and Churubusco).
1848, June 6 1st lieutenant, 2nd infantry.
1848-53 Served in California.
1853-61 Served in Minnesota, Nebraska and Kansas.
1855, Feb. 5 Captain, 2nd Infantry.
1861, May 14 Major, 11th Infantry.
1861 + During 1st year of Civil War, commanded a brigade at Wilson's Creek and other operations in Missouri.
1861, Sept. 23 Colonel of 8th Iowa Infantry (Volunteers).
1862, Jan. 29 Brigadier General of Volunteers.
1862 Arkansas campaign. Division commander of Curtis' Army of the Southwest.
1862, Nov. 29 Major General of Volunteers.
1863 Division commander in XIII Army Corps in operations against Chickasaw Bluffs and Arkansas Post. (Jan. 11)
1863, May-July 4 Division commander in XV Army Corps (Sherman's) in Vicksburg campaign.
1863, Sept.-1864 In command of forces in Arkansas.
1863, Sep 10 Capture of Little Rock.
1864, Mar.-May Red River Campaign, capture of Camden, battle of Jenkin's Ferry.
1865, Jan.-July Canby's campaign against Mobile, in command of forces in Alabama east of Mobile Bay.
1865, July-Oct. Commanded Western District of Texas with headquarters at Brownsville on the Rio Grande.
1865, Nov.-1867 Dec. Commanded Department of the Columbia.
1867, March 1 Mustered out as Major General of Volunteers; promoted to Lt. Colonel in the regular army Aug. 26, 1863 and Colonel July 28, 1866.
1868, Jan. 12 Died in San Mateo, California.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Adams, Edward Payson, d.1897.; Andrews, Christoppher Columbus, 1892-1922.; Asboth, Alexander Sandor, 1811-1868.; Ballard, D. P.; Black, Charles, 1839-1915.; Blair, Francis Preston, 1791-1876.; Canby, Edward Richard Sprigg, 1817-1873.; Christensen, Christian Thomsen.; Cortina, Juan Nepomuceno.; Custer, George Armstrong, 1839-1876.; Davidson, John Wynn, 1824-1881.; Dennis, Elias Smith, 1812-1894.; Emery, Frederic William.; Escobedo, Mariano, 1826-1902.; Ferguson, Samuel B.; Haight, J. William.; Harte, Bret, 1836-1902.; Halleck, Henry Wager, 1815-1872.; Halsted, Richard F.; Hawkins, John Parker, 1830-1914.; Herron, Francis Jay, 1837-1902.; Humphrey, Otis Milton.; Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875.; Juarez, Benito, 1806-1872.; Kent, Richard A.; Lacey, John Fletcher, 1841-1913.; Lawler, Michael Kelly, 1814-1882.; Leâon, Francisco Marâia de, 1799-1871.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Lucas, Thomas John, 1826-1908.; Lyman, Joseph, 1840-1890.; McClellan, George Brinton, 1826-1885.; McEntee, Charles Stuart.; Manter, Frederick H.; Marcy, Randolph Barnes, 1812-1887.; Mejâia, Thomâas, 1812-1867.; Miller, Stephen, 1816-1881.; Monroe, George.; Murphy, Isaac Burns, 1861-; Ord, Edward Otho Cresap, 1818-1888.; Osterhaus, Peter Joseph, 1823-1917.; Reynolds, Joseph Jones, 1822-1899.; Rhoades, Lawrence.; Sawtelle, Charles Greene.; Schofield, John McAllister, 1831-1906.; Scott, Robert Nicholson, d.1887.; Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888.; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891.; Spurling, Andrew Barday.; Stanton, Edwin McMasters, 1814-1869.; Steele, John Benedict, 1814-1866.; Storer, Newman W.; Totten, James, d.1871.; Townsend, Edward Davis, 1817-1893.; Warren, William Frederick.; Wheeler, Junius Brutus, d.1886.; Wilbur, George L.; Williams, George Henry, 1820-1910.; United States--Armed Forces--Afro-Americans.; Slavery--United States.; Afro-Americans.; United States--History--War with Mexico, 1845-1848.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Campaigns.; Indians of North America.; Texas.; Mexico.; Arkansas.; Oregon.
Collection Contents
- Series IA. Correspondence and papers of General Frederick Steele, 1845-1890.
  Includes 1 folder of miscellany. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1819, Feb. 11Ester and Peter St. John to Mrs. John Steele (Box 1, Folder 1.)
  - Correspondence 1819-1861. (Box 1, Folder 1a)
    - 1a. 1845, Sept. 9.FS & M. N. Steele to Em (Mrs. L.C. Steele). ALS. FS on furlough, murder of Osman Steele, FS starting with 40 men after chief Graham, family news.
    - 1b. [1855?], Feb. 15.Mrs. Geo. Terrill to [F]S. AN. Invitation
    - 2. 1855, Mar. 14.War Dept.-A.G.O. General Orders [G.O.] No. 3. Promotes FS to Capt. 2nd U. S. Infantry. True copy by Geo. D. Ruggles.
    - 3. [1855?], May 4.Anna F. Parker to [F]S. ALS. Thank you note
    - 4. 1858, July 28.Oscar L. Shafter, James McM. Shafter, T. W. Park, Solomon Heydenfeldt and Rensselaer E. Steele, Isaac C. Steele, George Steele, Edgar W. Steele. Indenture, DS. Lease of portion of Punta de los Reyes Ranch.
    - 5. 1858, Aug. 1.George W. Cullum-printed circular. re: Register of the Officers and Graduates of the U. S. Military Academy.
    - 6. 1858, Nov. 15.Dept. of the West. Special Orders [S.O.] No. 107. St. Louis, Mo. DS. Appointment of detail for court martial; s. D[on] C[arlos] Buell.
    - 7. 1859, Feb. 12.N. S. Crowell. DS. Certificate of attendance at court martial.
    - 8 & 9. 1859, Feb. 12.FS. 2 DSs. Printed and ms. forms for court martial service. Docket s. E. B. B. [Edwin Burr Babbitt?].
    - 10. 1859, Sept. 4.Alex. Wilkin to FS. ALS. Re: payment of a debt.
    - 11. 1859, Nov.Cameron Co., Texas - 12th Judicial District. Printed broadside. Report of the Grand Jury, On the Disturbances of the Country. A. B. Bacon, District Attorney.
    - 12. 1860, Feb. 23.FS to E. W. Steele. ALS. Death of their mother.
    - 13. 1861, Sept. 12Maj. Sturgis - Official report [8/20/61] of Battle of Wilson's Creek [8/10/61]. Clipping from The Republican, St. Louis.
    - 14. 1861, Sept.FS - Official Report of Dug Spring Fight, etc. (8/2/61. Clipping.
    - 15. 1861, Nov. 21.[FS] to Miss Anna [Parker?]. AL Re: Fremont's failure, Battle of Wilson's Creek, death of Gen. Lyon.
    - 16. 1861, Dec. 31.A. Lincoln to Secretary of War [Stanton]. [Verifax?] of ALS. Recommends appointment of FS as Brigadier General of Volunteers with ANS of S[imon] C[ameron].
  - Correspondence 1862, January-March. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1. [1862], Jan. 3.Jno. Pope to FS. ALS. Sedalia orders, FS to be Brigadier General.
    - 2. 1862, Jan. 8.Jno. Pope to FS. ALS. Military and personal.
    - 3. 1862, Jan. 20.John B. Steele - The Slavery Question. Reprint of speech delivered in the U. S. House of Representatives.
    - 4. 1862, Feb. 16.S. E. Meigs - Supply Invoice. DS.
    - 5. 1862, Feb. 28.[Army] Headquarters, Cairo, Illinois. S.O. No. 20. DS. FS to report to St. Louis. Signed Geo. W. Cullum.
    - 6. 1862, Feb. 28.Wm. Myers - List of supplies received by FS. DS.
    - 7. 1862, Mar. 6.See No. 5 above.
    - 8. 1862, Mar. 13.H. W. Halleck to FS. Tel.
    - 9. 1862, Mar. [16].G. R. Dyer - Stores Receipt. DS.
    - 10. [1862, Mar.?].Quarter Master's Stores - Monthly return.
  - Correspondence 1862, April-December. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 186 1862, Apr. 7.G. [W.] [Sproule] - Stores receipt. DS.
    - 2. 1862, Apr. 13.Edwin [U. Sheldon?]. to FS. ALS. Re: C. T. Scammon.
    - 3. 1862, Apr. 14.G. [W. Sproule] - Stores receipt. D.S.
    - 4. 1862, Jun. 22. Tratado de Extradicion entre los Estados-Unidos Mexicanos y los Estados-Unidos de America. Printed.
    - 5. 1862, Sept. 1.O. L. Shafter et al to E. Steele et al. DS. Indenture-land lease for part of Puenta [sic] de los Reyes Ranch, Marin Co., California.
    - 6. 1862, Nov. 1.[FS?] to General. ADf of letter. Maneuvers in Arkansas, military, politics.
    - 7. [1862?,] Nov. 11.S. R. Curtis to FS. ANS. Extract from Blount [sic] (Blunt) to Schofield describing the Arkansas situation.
    - 8. 1862, Nov. 11.G. A. Mitchell to [FS]. ALS.
    - 9. 1862, Nov. 12.FS to Gen. Curtis. ALS. Rumors spread by rebels, Little Rock, etc.
    - 10. 1862, Dec. 17.W. T. Sherman to FS. ALS. Organization of forces, Grant, Yazoo River area campaign plans.
    - 11. 1862, Dec. 21.11th U. S. Infantry - Circular. DS. Re: regimental band. Signed G. N. Lieber.
    - 12. 1862, Dec. 26.J. Horne, notary, et al. ADS. Re: FS's order surrendering fugitive slaves at Helena, [Arkansas] 9/4/62 and the circumstances of its execution.
    - 13. [1862?].H. W. Halleck to FS. [ALS?]. Orders to move towards Salem and Gen. Curtis.
  - Correspondence 1863, January-June. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1. 1863, Jan. 22. Abraham Lincoln to FS. LS. FS's promotion. [Located in safe].
    - 2a. [1863,] Jan 30.Ellen M. McClellan to FS. ALS. Wants autograph to auction at Sanitary Fair.
    - 2, 3a & 3b. 1863, Feb. 15.[FS] to [A. Lincoln]. ADf and 2 unsigned (1 partial copy) copies. FS's defense to Forman's charges, conditions in Helena, fugitive slaves.
    - 4. 1863, Feb. 22.John M. Thayer to [A. Lincoln]. ALS. Character witness for FS.
      [# 86 should follow]
    - 5. 1863, Apr. 11.Loyal Publication Society. Printed address. Read at inaugural meeting of the Loyal National League at the request of the League.
    - 6. [1863,] May 1.Vicksburg, Miss, Holograph map by Juls. Pitzman. Shows Sherman's attack, FS's Division, Blair's Division, etc.
    - 7. 1863, May 1-3. Near Chancellorsville. Holograph map of the battles by A. Pohlers.
    - 8a. 1863, May 3.Irwin McDowell to FS. LS. Court of Inquiry re: traffic in cotton, etc.
    - 8b. 1863, Mar. 17.A. Lincoln and E. M. Stanton. Copy of DS. Appointment of FS as Major General of Volunteers. Original owned by Wilfred Steele. Oversize. [Located in map drawer]. [Out of place, should follow #4.]
    - 9. [1863, May].Jackson, [Miss.]. Pencil map indicating routes.
    - 10. [1863, May].Jackson, [Miss.]. Pencil map with interesting notations.
    - 11. [1863, May].Haines Bluff, [Miss.]. Holograph detail map.
    - 12. [1863, May-July].Vicksburg, [Miss.] and Area. Holograph map by Juls. Pitzman. Many additions. Shows south to Port Gibson, north to Haines Bluff, west to Richmond, and east to Raymond.
    - 13. 1863, June 9.A[lexander] D[allas] Bache to FS. LS. Re: operations map of Vicksburg.
    - 14. [1863, June 9?].Louisiana 1855. Printed map with pencil notations indicating it was used at Vicksburg.
    - 15. 1863, June 21.W. T. Sherman to FS. ALS. Thanks for present of Duke. [horse].
    - 16. 1863, June 24.W. M. Voglison [sic]. ADS. Receipt for 44 cases of Sparkling Catawba Wine. NS of A. J. Smith.
    - 17. 1863, June 28. To Our Friends in Vicksburg. Printed broadside. Propaganda
  - Correspondence 1863, July-August. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1. 1863, July 24.C[harles] E[dward] Hovey to FS. ALS. Re: appointment of Hovey.
    - 3. [1863, July?]. Historical Sketch of the Rebellion. Printed map.
    - 4. [1863, July].Vicksburg, [Miss.]. Printed map by U. S. Coast Survey Office, shows U. S. operations.
    - 5. [1863, July?].[Vicksburg, Miss.]. Holograph map showing artillery, mortar and gunboat positions.
    - 6. [1863, July].Yazoo, [Miss.]. Holograph map showing south to Vicksburg, north to Lake Bolivar, and west to Lake Providence.
    - 7. 1863, Aug. 9.[FS] to J[ohn] W[ynn] Davidson. ADF Reports re: Arkansas, FS's career.
    - 8. 1863, Aug. 11.[FS] to Unknown [Gen'l. _____?]. ADF Re: Davidson, military situation and plans, White River, Arkansas expedition.
    - 9. [1863, Aug. 11].[DeValls Bluff, Ark.]. Holograph map.
    - 10. 1863, Aug. 12.J. W. Paddock to FS. ALS.
    - 11. 1863, Aug. 13.FS. ADS. Certifies remuneration claims.
    - 12. 1863, Aug. 13.[FS] to Unknown [Gen. _____?]. ADF Plans re: Little Rock.
    - 13. 1863, Aug. 21.C[harles] R[obert] Woods to FS. ALS. Re: horses.
    - 14. 1863, Aug. 27.U. S. Grant to FS. ALS. Re: 3rd Iowa Cavalry..
  - Correspondence 1863, September. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1. 1863, Sept. 12.FS - Official Report of Operations in Arkansas. ADf.
    - 2. 1863, Sept. 12.FS. Galley of #1.
    - 3. 1863, Sept. 22.FS to J. M. Scofield. ALS. Supplementary report to that of 9/12. Operation against Little Rock.
    - 4. 1863, Sept. 23.[FS] to H. W. Halleck. Unsigned copy.
    - 5. 1863, Sept. 25.Edwin M. Stanton. Doc., stamped? Appointment of FS as Lt. Colonel in the 3rd U. S. Infantry.
    - 6. 1863, Sept. 28.Frank P. Blair, Jr. to FS. ALS.
  - Correspondence 1863, October-November. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1a. 1863, Oct. 13.War Dept.-A.G.O. G. O. No. 336. Printed. Military commission, trials of Thomas Kane and Wm. McNellis.
    - 1b. 1863, Oct. 16.Ella Steele to Edgar Steele. Xerox of ALS. Reference to FS.
    - 2. 1863, Oct. 18.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 1. Printed. U. S. Grant takes command of Division. s. T. H. Harris. (Folder 8)
    - 3. 1863, Oct. 18.[FS] to J.[sic] M. Stanton. ADf. Recommends Col. Glover.
    - 4. 1863, Oct. 19.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 2. Printed. Sherman to command Department and Army of the Tennessee. s. T. H. Harris.
    - 5. 1863, Oct. 19.[FS] to J. M. Schofield. ADf.
    - 6. 1863, Oct. 19.War Department - A.G.O. G.O. No. 340. Printed. Proclamation by the President calling for 3000000 volunteers.
    - 7. 1863, Oct. 19.War Department - A.G.O. G. O. 343. Printed. General court martial - Sam'l Ford.
    - 8. 1863, Oct. 11.FS to J. M. Schofield. ALS.
    - 9. 1863, Oct. 11.FS to S. A. Hurlbut. ALS.
    - 10. 1863, Nov. [9].FS to J. Richmond. ADf. Re: guerrillas.
    - 11. 1863, Nov. 9.[FS] to J. M. Schofield. ADf. Arkansas, troops, spies.
    - 12. 1863, Nov. 9.[FS] to W. T. Sherman. ADf. to hold the Line of the Arkansas.
    - 13. 1863, Nov. 12.Military Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 6. Printed. s. T. S. Bowers.
    - 14. 1863, Nov. 18.FS to J. M. Schofield. ALS. Cavalry expedition to White River, Benton.
    - 15. 1863, Nov. 23.J. W. Davidson to FS. ALS.
    - 16. 1863, Nov. 24.Thos. W. Knox to [FS?]. ALS. Re: prisoner exchange.
  - Correspondence 1863, December. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1. 1863, Dec. 7.Unknown [not signed] to S. M. Breckenridge. Copy in holograph. Recommends plan of operations in Louisiana and Texas. Docket 12/26/63 s. J. C. Kelton.
    - 2. 1863, Dec. 8.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 7. Printed. Telegram from Lincoln. s. T. S. Bowers.
    - 3. 1863, Dec. 9.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 8. Printed.
    - 4. 1863, Dec. 9.Miss M. S. Worth to FS. ALS. Citizens of Albany [N.Y.] propose to organize a fair and request FS's autograph.
    - 5. 1863, Dec. 10.G. L. Miller to FS. ALS. FS's policy in Arkansas.
    - 6. 1863, Dec. 11.J. M. Schofield to FS. ALS. Re: Banks, reinforcements.
    - 7. 1863, Dec. 12.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 10. Printed. Policy re: Confederate deserters.
    - 8. 1863, Dec. 12.[FS] to J. M. Schofield. ADf. Reason for scattered troops.
    - 9. 1863, Dec. 15.Th. H. Yeatman to FS. LS.
    - 10. 1863, Dec. 10.W. W. Wilshire. ADS. Receipt for tax on cotton, enclosed in #9.
    - 11. 1863, Dec. 16.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 12. Printed. s. Geo. O. Sokalski.
    - 12a. 1863, Dec. 18.Geo. B. Peters to FS. ALS.
    - 12b. 1863, Dec. 22.C. E. Hovey to FS et al. ALS.
    - 13. 1863, Dec. 23.Th. H. Yeatman to FS. LS. Application to ship cotton, fraud situation as seen by Treasury agent.
    - 14. 1863, Dec. 29.T. T. Crittenden to [FS]. ALS.
    - 15. 1863, Dec. 29.Th. H. Yeatman to FS. LS. More on cotton fraud.
    - 16. 1863, Dec. 30.W. N. Hood to FS. ALS. Destruction of property, compansation.
    - 17. 1863, Dec.Documents. Copies. Re: shipping cotton, permit.
    - 18. [1863?].Vickaburg, [Miss.]. Clipping. Fragment of article.
    - 19. [1863-64?].Thos. C. Anderson to FS. ALS. Requests permission to ship plantation supplies.
  - Correspondence 1864, January. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1. 1864, Jan. 2.J. G. Dunlap to C. T. Christensen. ANS. Referred and s. C. T. C. to FS.
    - 2. 1864, Jan. 5.Abraham Lincoln to FS. LS. Re: Arkansas, oath, re-organization of state government. [Located in safe].
    - 3. [1864], Jan. 7.E. W. [Gantt] to FS. ALS. Re: Arkansas, politics, personal.
    - 4. 1864, Jan. 7.War Department - A.G.O. Printed request for military history. s. [Samuel] Breck.
    - 5. 1864, Jan. 8.Harriet C. [Norrland] to FS. ALS. Plea for life of a Confederate soldier.
    - 6. [1864], Jan. 8.H. C. Norrland et al to FS. ALS. Plea for life of spy.
    - 7a. 1864, Jan. 8.FS to Ladies. ADf. Plea came too late.
    - 7b. 1864, Jan. 11.U. S. Sanitary Commission, California Branch to Steele Brothers. Photo of certificate for $2,850 obtained for cheese. s. Henry W. Bellows, F. F. Low, R. G. Sneath and O. C. Wheeler. [Original belongs to donor].
    - 8. 1864, Jan. 14.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Re: reviving slavery in Arkansas would require another revolution.
    - 9. 1864, Jan. [17?].[FS] to Admiral D[avid] Porter. ADf. Shipping.
    - 10. 1864, Jan. 18.War Department - A.G.O. Printed circular re: invalids.
    - 11. 1864, Jan. 19.J[osiah] Snow and I[saac] C. Mills to FS. ALS. of Mills. Washington, D. C., Arkansas, Steeles.
    - 12. 1864, Jan. 20.Abraham Lincoln to FS. LS. Arkansas petition for an election, agrees to. [Located in safe].
    - 13. 1864, Jan. 20.Dosiah Snow to FS. ALS. Arkansas a separate department, FS commander.
    - 14. 1864, Jan. 20.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Re: command of Arkansas, FS's support in Washington.
    - 15. 1864, Jan. 21.S. A. Hurlbut to FS. ALS. Requests Brig. Gen. Kimball be ordered to report to him [S.A.H.]
    - 16. 1864, Jan. 21.[FS] to I. Murphy. ADf. Aska opinion of his conciliatory policy.
    - 17. 1864, Jan. 21.Convention of Delegates of The People of Arkansas to FS. ALS. by Sec. R. J. T. White.
    - 17a. 1864, Jan. 22.E. Bexter to FS. ALS with NS by John Good. Introduction.
    - 18. 1864, Jan. 22.Isaac Murphy to FS. ALS. Re: conciliatory policy in Arkansas.
    - 19. 1864, Jan. 24.Jas. Harrison to FS. ALS. NS on docket by J. M. Schofield.
    - 20. 1864, Jan. 26.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Advice, family, destroyed letters of FS re: Davidson.
    - 21. 1864, Jan. 27.S. H. Boyd to F[S]. ALS. Re: Davidson, himself.
    - 22. 1864, Jan. 27.Abraham Lincoln to FS. ALS. Private re: Gantt, Arkansas Convention, possible clash with Lincoln's policy. [Located in safe].
    - 23. 1864, Jan. 30.Department of Arkansas. G.O.No. 1. Printed. Re: Department, command and 7th Army Corps.
    - 24. 1864, Jan. 30.Abraham Lincoln to FS. ALS. Re: Arkansas, FS to use his judgement. [Located in safe].
    - 25. 1864, Jan. 30.[FS] to T. H. Holmes. ADf. Communication with Confederate commander of Arkansas.
    - 26. 1864, Jan. 31.Chas. H. Willson to [Edgar Steele?]. ALS. Return East from California.
    - 27. [1864, Jan.].Mary Field Knapp et al to FS. ALS. Petition of the ladies of Little Rock for pardon of David O. Dodd, condemned to be hung as a spy.
    - 28. [1864, Jan.?].Isaac Murphy to FS. ALS. Proposed order for propection of voters.
    - 29. [1864, Jan.?].Wm. D. Snow. Printed broadside of an address with ANS on Verso to [FS].
    - 30. [1864, Jan.?].[FS] to Unknown. Df. of letter of introduction
  - Correspondence 1864, February. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1. 1864, Feb. 1.J. W. Davidson to FS. ALS.
    - 2. 1864, Feb. 1.FS to J. W. Davidson. ALS.
    - 3. 1864, Feb. 2.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 2. Printed. Re: Proclamation Oath of Allegiance.
    - 4. 1864, Feb. 2.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 2. Re: shipping horses and mules.
    - 5. 1864, Feb. 2.FS to A. Lincoln. tel.S Re: date of Arkansas election.
    - 6. 1864, Feb. 4.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 3. Printed.
    - 7. 1864, Feb. 4.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 3. Printed. Re: manager of railways.
    - 8. 1864, Feb. 4.FS to N. P. Banks. LS (part in FS's hand). Re: enemy forage stations, etc., possibly to move against Pine Bluff.
    - 9. 1864, Feb. 4.War Department - A.G.O. Printed circular.
    - 10. 1864, Feb. 6.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 4. Printed. Re: pilots.
    - 11. 1864, Feb. 6.[FS] to H. W. Halleck. AL. Rebels arming.
    - 12. 1864, Feb. 7.Department of Arkansas. G.O. No. 4. Printed.
    - 13. 1864, Feb. 8.J. M. Johnson to I. Murphy. ALS. Re: President's desire to aid [Arkansas].
    - 14. 1864, Feb. 9.R. P. Buckland to FS. LS. Enemy making preparations to attack Little Rock.
    - 15. 1864, Feb. 10.Dept. of Arkansas.- Provost Marshall. G.O. No. 1. Printed.
    - 16. 1864, Feb. 11.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Re: Sickles.
    - 17. 1864, Feb. 12.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 5. Printed. Re: trade regulations.
    - 18. 1864, Feb. 12.John B. Steele to [FS]. ALS. Re: Sickles.
    - 19. 1864, Feb. 13.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 5. Printed.
    - 20. 1864, Feb. 13.FS to Loyal Case. ALS. Re: Mr. Merrick.
    - 21. 1864, Feb. 13.War Department - A.G.O. Printed circular. Recruiting bounty.
    - 22. 1864, Feb. 14.Edw. Bates to James Harrison. ALS. Pacification policies.
    - 23. 1864, Feb. 14.Jos. R. Smith to [FS?]. ALS. Re: Hammond Court Martial, etc.
    - 24. 1864, Feb. 15.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 6. Printed. Re: guard on steamboats.
    - 25. 1864, Feb. 17.Department of Arkansas. G.O. No. 7. Printed Re: abandoned property.
    - 26. [1864?], Feb. 17.M. Guthrie to FS. ALS. Asks favor.
    - 27. 1864, Feb. 19.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 8. Printed.
    - 28. 1864, Feb. 20.Isaac W. Arnold to [FS]. ALS. Asks intercession and protection of Col. Hartman.
    - 29. 1864, Feb. 20.C. P. Bertrand to A. Lincoln. ALS. Re: Sickles.
    - 30. 1864, Feb. 20.James Harrison to FS. ALS. Re: FS's military policy.
    - 31. 1864, Feb. 20.Recruits (unassigned) to FS. ADS. Petition with ANS recommend of Isaac Murphy.
    - 32. 1864, Feb. 23.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 9. Printed. Collecting and organizing negroes.
    - 33. 1864, Feb. 25.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 6. Printed. Hiring negroes.
    - 34. 1864, Feb. 25.[FS] to H. W. Halleck. L. Rebels in Arkansas, etc.
    - 35. 1864, Feb. 25.J. B. Wheeler to FS. ALS.
    - 36. [1864,?] Feb. 26.Mrs. Anderson to FS. ALS. Thank you.
    - 37. 1864, Feb. 26.Division of the Mississippi. G.O. No. 6. Printed. Same as that for Feb. 25.
    - 38-39. 1864, Feb. 27.Mrs. E. Kirby Smith to FS. ALS and copy with AN.
    - 40-41. 1864, Feb. 27.[FS] ADf. Announcing election in Arkansas and proclamation ADf.
    - 42. 1864, Feb. 28.[FS] to N. P. Banks. AL. FS's troops, election, rebels line of defense - Red River.
    - 43. 1864, Feb. 29.FS to People of Arkansas. DS. Proclamation re: election.
    - 44. 1864, Feb. 29.FS - Proclamation. Printed version of #43, with election schedule.
    - 45. 1864, Feb. 29.John M. Thayer to FS. ALS. Report re: Kansas Regiments in the Dept. of Arkansas, horses, forage, Ft. Smith.
    - 46. 1864, Feb.Dept. of the Gulf. Map No. 14. Eastern and Central Texas. Printed on linen.
    - 47. 1864, Feb.Maryland State Fair. Printed announcement. ANS of Mrs. Amos[Binney]on verso requesting autograph.
    - 48. [1864, Feb.?].FS to Unknown [Fragment, 1st page missing]. Copy s. W. D. Green.
  - Correspondence 1864, March. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1. 1864, Mar. 1.A. I. Magill to FS. ALS. Request for mail from a rebel.
    - 2. 1864, Mar. 2.Mrs. E. Miller to FS. ALS. Re: oath and purchasing.
    - 3. 1864, Mar. 3.Dept. of Arkansas. G.O. No. 10. Printed. Wm. E. Woodruff, citizen - confederate takes oath to keep from starving.
    - 4. 1864, Mar. 3.G. L. Miller to [FS]. ALS. Views on political and social aspect of Arkansas, FS.
    - 5. 1864, Mar. 4.M. D. Lancey Landon to [FS]. ALS. Re: Gen. Buford.